Educational Opportunity Center; Records ua561
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Educational Opportunity Center
1959-1978
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
ua561
1.8 ft. cubic ft.
This collection is comprised of the inactive records from the Educational Opportunity Center at the State University of New York at Albany.
Content Description
The collection documents the procedures of the Educational Opportunity Center (EOC) from 1973 to 1978 and contains reports, budgets, correspondence, data, surveys, audits, memos, plans, projects, reports, program materials, and more. Earlier records of the EOC from the late 1960s to early 1970s were destroyed by a water leakage at EOC and could not be donated to the Archives. Files titled as "Important Documents" may include enrollment information, program proposals and reports, memos, surveys, evaluations, budgets and fiscal reports, student data, correspondence, and more.
Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records of the Educational Opportunity Center were transferred to the Archives in May of 1978.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is arranged chronologically. There are no series.
Historical Note
The Educational Opportunity Center (EOC) at the State University of New York at Albany provided free programs for economically or educationally disadvantaged adults in the Albany area in order to further their careers and/or educational goals from the late 1960s to late 1970s. Vocational programs included bookkeeping/accounting, clerk typing, keypunch operation, office assistant jobs, and secretarial work. Free academic programs included English-as-a-Second-Language courses, vocational preparation, high school equivalency, and health science programs. After completion of a program, the EOC worked to place graduates in jobs or college.
These records pertain to the program as it was offered by the State University of New York at Albany before it was consolidated in 1978 with the Troy Educational Opportunity Center. Operations were combined under the management of Hudson Valley Community College and still operate today, under the name Capital District Opportunity Center. In May of 1978, the records of the Educational Opportunity Center were transferred to the Archives as a result of the consolidation of EOCs and the end of State University of New York at Albany's administrative responsibility in August of 1978.
Educational Opportunity Center (State University of New York); UAlbany Centers & Institutes; Education; Albany, New York; Career development; Administrative records
- 1973 Summative Reports and Testing Materials, 1959; 1963; Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Communications: EOC- Guidelines, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Audits and Reports, 1973; Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Communications: EOC- Material or Correspondence from Other Centers, 1973; Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Original Reports, 1973; Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Communications: EOC- Miscellaneous, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Communications: EOC- Policies and Procedures, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- EOC Reports, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Communications: Drug Education Program, EOC, 1973-1974; Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Communications: EOC- Academic Affairs (Programs), 1973-1974; Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Communications: EOC- Budget and Financial Matters, 1973-1974; Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Communications: EOC- Personnel, 1973-1975; Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Important Documents: Budgets, Reports, Memos, Data, 1973-1976; Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Important Documents: Placement, Reports, Data, Policies, 1973-1976; Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Important Documents, 1973-1977; Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Recruiting for Summer and Fall Courses, 1974 July 3 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Communications: EOC- Inventories, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- EOC Screening Committee Memos and Miscellaneous Information, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Year End Reports, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- 74-75 Budget, 1974; Undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Important Documents: Memos, Reports, Information, 1974; Undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Important Documents: Program Evaluations, Assessments, and Reports, 1974-1975; Undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
- 75-76 Budget, 1974-1976; Undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
- 75-77 Budgets and Planning, 1974-1976; Undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Project Mercury, 1974-1976; Undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Questionnaires Received After Survey Was Finished, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Project Mercury Final Report, 1975; Undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Veterans Survey of Vocational Programs and Student Lists, 1975; Undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
- EOC Organization, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- 76-77 Budget (1 of 2), 1975-1976; Undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
- 76-77 Budget (2 of 2), 1975-1976; Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Important Documents, 1975-1976; Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Important Documents: Program Information, Reports, and Memos, 1975-1976; Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Important Documents: Reports, Surveys, Enrollment, and Program Information, 1975-1976; Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Essential Documents, 1975-1977; Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Includes annual reports, final reports, brochures, enrollment information, program results, and memos.
- Destroyed Files, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Job Preparation Handbook, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Important Documents: Burns International Security Services, Inc., 1976; Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Important Documents: Program Information and Surveys, 1976; Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Monthly Reports, 1976; Undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Important Documents, 1976-1978; Undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
- 74-75 and 75-76 Budget Requests, Undated (Box 4, Folder 2)